Guide to the Hugh Byas papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Hugh Byas papers
1928-1941
MS 121
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11
(microfilm - 11,210 frames)
Scrapbooks, writings and research files on 11 reels of microfilm (HM 95). The research files consist of pamphlets, periodicals, newspaper clippings and news bulletins on all aspects of Japanese life which were compiled for lectures at Yale University, 1941-1945, and for use in a book which was never published. The scrapbooks contain clippings of his articles which appeared in The Times (London), The New York Times and The Japan Times and Mail, 1928-1939. Also a small number of drafts of articles written between 1932 and 1939.
Byas, Hugh, 1875-1945
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Hugh Byas, 1948.
Scope and Contents
Scrapbooks, writings and research files on 11 reels of microfilm (HM 95). The research files consist of pamphlets, periodicals, newspaper clippings and news bulletins on all aspects of Japanese life which were compiled for lectures at Yale University, 1941-1945, and for use in a book which was never published. The scrapbooks contain clippings of his articles which appeared in The Times (London), The New York Times and The Japan Times and Mail, 1928-1939. Also a small number of drafts of articles written between 1932 and 1939. Originals were discarded after filming.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Journalism; Asia; Japan -- History -- 1912-1945; Manchuria (China) -- History -- 1931-1945; Journalists; Baldwin, Hanson Weightman, 1903-1991; Byas, Hugh, 1875-1945; Cholmondeley, Lionel Berners, b. 1858 or 9; Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1891-1968; Young, Arthur Morgan, 1874-
- Inventory, 1928-1941
  Scope and Contents
  Newspaper correspondent. Scrapbooks, writings and research files. The latter, consisting of pamphlets, periodicals, newspaper clippings and news bulletins on all aspects of Japanese life were compiled for lectures at Yale University, 1941-1945, and for use in a book which was never published. The scrapbooks contain clippings of his articles which appeared in The Times (London), The New York Times and The Japan Times and Mail, 1928-1939. Also a small number of drafts of articles written between 1932 and 1939.
  Microfilm, New Haven, Yale University Library, 1980.
  - Scrapbooks of newspaper clippings
    - The Times (London), 1928 February 19-1941 February (Box 1)
    - The New York Times, 1931 May 22-1933 December (Box 1)
    - The New York Times, 1933 December 14-1939 November (Box 2)
    - The New York Times, 1939 November 9-1941 March (Box 2)
  - Loose newspaper clippings
    - The Japan Times & Mail, 1932 January 21-22 (Box 2)
    - The New York Times, 1939 April 30 (Box 2)
  - Drafts of articles, 1932 - 1939, undated (Box 2)
  - Loose newspaper clippings
    - The New York Times Magazine, 1930 March 23- 1940 January (Box 2)
  - SUBJECT FILES - Series A
    - Agriculture, 1915-1917 (Box 3)
    - "Ainu" (Box 3)
    - Anglo-Japanese Relations, 1927-1936 (Box 3)
    - Architecture, 1922-1929 (Box 3)
    - Army, 1934-1941 (Box 3)
    - Army - National Defense, 1935-1941 (Box 3)
    - Articles by various Japanese, 1931-1933, undated (Box 3)
    - Asiatic Outlook, 1942 (Box 3)
    - Aviation, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
    - Axis Alliance, 1940 (Box 3)
    - Biographies, 1930-1940 (Box 3)
    - Censorship, 1920-1941 (Box 3)
    - Christianity, 1919-1933 (Box 3)
    - Color and Race Problems, 1925-1927 (Box 3)
    - Communism, 1931-1940 (Box 4)
    - Constitution (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1916-1942 (Box 4)
    - Cost of Living, 1918-1939 (Box 4)
    - Cotton, 1933 (Box 4)
    - Crime - Juvenile Delinquency, 1931 (Box 4)
    - Darien Piracy Case, 1933-1934 (Box 4)
    - Drama, 1920-1939 (Box 4)
    - Earthquake, 1923 (Box 4)
    - Economic conditions, 1937-1941 (Box 4)
    - Education, 1921-1940 (Box 4)
    - Emigration, 1929-1937 (Box 4)
    - Emperor, The
      - Coronation, 1915 (Box 4)
      - Enthronement, 1928 (Box 4)
      - Reinterpretation, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Espionage, 1936-1940 (Box 4)
    - "Eta", 1922-1927 (Box 4)
    - European War, 1914-1918 (Box 4)
    - Expansion, 1919-1936 (Box 4)
    - Expansion in the Pacific, 1935-1940 (Box 5)
    - Extra-territoriality, 1928-1943 (Box 5)
    - Family System, 1921-1938 (Box 5)
    - Foreign Policy, 1919-1941 (Box 5)
    - Foreign relations, 1917-1941 (Box 5)
    - Foreign views of Japan, 1931-1935 (Box 5)
    - Geisha Girl, 1918-1922 (Box 5)
    - Government, 1929-1939 (Box 5)
    - Health, 1928-1935 (Box 5)
    - Ise, Grand Shrine of, 1926 (Box 5)
    - International gleanings, 1936-1941 (Box 5)
    - Journalism, 1916-1941 (Box 5)
    - Kokusai and Domei News Agency, 1911-1937 (Box 5)
    - Korea, 1920-1937 (Box 6)
    - Labor, 1914-1940 (Box 6)
    - Language, 1922-1931 (Box 6)
    - Law, 1929-1940 (Box 6)
    - Lectures in C.A.T.S., Yale University, 1944 (Box 6)
    - Leprosy, 1919-1936 (Box 6)
    - Liberalism, 1920-1931 (Box 6)
    - Literature, 1922-1940 (Box 6)
    - Manchukuo, 1932-1933 (Box 6)
    - Marriage and divorce, 1921-1941 (Box 6)
    - Memorials, 1927-1936 (Box 6)
    - Military Rescript, 1940 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1916-1941 (Box 6)
    - Mitsui Family (Box 7)
    - Mobilization, 1938-1940 (Box 7)
    - Music (Box 7)
    - National Characteristics, 1922-1938 (Box 7)
    - Nationality status, 1918-1935 (Box 7)
    - Navy, 1927-1937 (Box 7)
    - Navy - History, 1921-1940 (Box 7)
    - The New East (publication), 1916-1918 (Box 7)
    - New Political Structure, 1939-1940 (Box 7)
    - Pan-Asianism, 1926-1935 (Box 7)
    - Periodicals, 1935 (Box 7)
    - Philosophy, 1921-1940 (Box 7)
    - Photographs (Box 7)
    - Police, 1936-1937 (Box 7)
    - Political System, 1920 (Box 7)
    - Politics, 1912-1941 (Box 8)
    - Population, 1931-1940 (Box 8)
    - Press regulations and military secrets, laws, 1916-1939 (Box 8)
    - Propaganda, 1934-1939 (Box 8)
    - Prostitution, 1931-1940 (Box 8)
    - Reactionary societies, 1932-1934 (Box 8)
    - Religion, 1922-1940 (Box 8)
    - Russia, 1933-1936 (Box 8)
    - Russo-Japanese relations (Box 8)
    - Scandals, 1918-1935 (Box 9)
    - Short stories by various Japanese (Box 9)
    - Sino-Japanese relations, 1935-1940 (Box 9)
    - Slums, 1921-1937 (Box 9)
    - Suicide, 1921-1939 (Box 9)
    - Toyama, Mitsuru (Box 9)
    - Trade, 1927-1935 (Box 9)
    - Women, 1922-1938 (Box 9)
    - Yokohama leaseholds, 1927 (Box 9)
    - Young Men's Association, 1925-1935 (Box 9)
  - SUBJECT FILES - Series B
    - [General] (Box 10)
    - Army (Box 10)
    - Aviation; Communications; Geography (Box 10)
    - Japanese Cinema (Box 10)
    - Japanese Constitution (Box 10)
    - Continental Policy (Box 10)
    - Education; Journalism (Box 10)
    - Emigration (Box 10)
    - Emperor (Box 10)
    - Family System (Box 10)
    - Farm (Box 10)
    - Food; Population (Box 10)
    - Foreign Policy (Box 10)
    - Future of Japan (Box 10)
    - Government (Box 10)
    - Harakiri (Box 10)
    - Historical Background (Box 10)
    - History (Box 11)
    - Industry (Box 11)
    - Japanese film "Cavalcade" (Box 11)
    - Korea (Box 11)
    - Labor (Box 11)
    - Liberal Decade (Box 11)
    - Local Government (Box 11)
    - Japanese Magazines and Modern Fiction (Box 11)
    - Modern Japan (Box 11)
    - Newspapers (Box 11)
    - Patriotic Societies (Box 11)
    - Political Systems (Box 11)
    - Religion (Box 11)
    - 1936 Revolt (Box 11)
    - Road to War (Box 11)
    - Russia [Relations with] (Box 11)
    - Southward [Policy] (Box 11)
    - Tanaka Memorial; Fifth Column; Miscellaneous Notes (Box 11)
    - Utilities (Box 11)
    - What to do with Japan (Box 11)